A Guide to the Resources for American Literary Study Collection 1970-1976
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Resources for American Literary Study Collection 1973-1976
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 37
25.2 linear feet
Drs. Maurice Duke and Thomas Inge.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated to the Department by the journal's editors Drs. Maurice Duke and Thomas Inge between the years 1973 and 1980.
Biographical/Historical Information
This is a collection of manuscripts and articles found in Resources for American Literary Study.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists of manuscripts and proofs of the articles in Volumes I-VI of Resources for American Literary Study (1973-1976). There is also some editorial correspondence. Resources was published biannually by VCU and the University of Maryland.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically by volume and issue. Articles within each issue are arranged alphabetically by author.
Contents List
- Title page Design, Editorial copy and Table of Contents 1971 (Box-folder 1.1)
- News release with corrections 1970 (Box-folder 1.2)
- Fugitive/Agrarian Materials in the Joint University Libraries M.E. Cooke and T.D. Young 1971 (Box-folder 1.3)
- The Reviewer: A Bibliographic Guide to a Little Magazine Maurice Duke 1971 (Box-folder 1.4)
- Critical Studies of William Faulkner's Light in August: An Annotated Checklist M. Thomas Inge 1971 (Box-folder 1.5-1.6)
- The Childs Collection Henry Miller at Randolph-Macon College Edgar E. MacDonald 1971 (Box-folder 1.7)
- The Background of the Hawthorne-Thoreau Relationship Edward C. Peple, Jr. 1971 (Box-folder 1.8)
- The State of Reference Bibliography in American Literature G. Thomas Tanselle 1971 (Box-folder 1.9)
- William Carlos Williams Linda W. Wagner 1970 (Box-folder 1.10)
- Book Reviews 1971 (Box-folder 1.11)
- Galley Proof Oversize 1971 (Box-folder 1.12)
- Galley Proof photocopy 1971 (Box-folder 1.13)
- Page Proof Oversize 1971 (Box-folder 1.14)
- Correspondence 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1.15)
- Galley Proofs Oversize 1971 (Box-folder 2.1)
- Page Proofs 1971, Oversize (Box-folder 2.2)
- Page Proofs 1971, oversize (Box-folder 2.3)
- Photocopies 1971 (Box-folder 2.4)
- Index Volume I 1971 (Box-folder 2.5)
- Cover and Front piece Design, Volume II, number 1 1972 (Box-folder 2.6)
- I Find the Real American Tragedy Theodore Drieser, n.d. (Box-folder 2.7)
- A Thomas Hooker Sermon of 1638 Everett Emerson (Box-folder 2.8)
- The Manuscript of Frank Norris McTeague Joseph Katz 1972 (Box-folder 2.9)
- Abraham Lincoln Collection at Iowa John Newman 1972 (Box-folder 2.10)
- Stephen Crane at Lafayatte D.E.E. Sloane 1972 (Box-folder 2.11)
- Book Reviews 1972 (Box-folder 2.12)
- Galley Proofs Book Reviews 1972 (Box-folder 2.13)
- News Notes 1972 (Box-folder 2.14)
- Page Proofs 1972, oversize (Box-folder 2.15)
- Notes, Correspondence and Miscellaneous Additions 1972 (Box-folder 2.16)
- Contents Page, Advertising Copy and Correspondence 1972 (Box-folder 2.17)
- Additions, Correspondence and Notes regarding Ezra Pound Criticism Checklist 1972 (Box-folder 2.18)
- Addenda and Index to Ezra Pound Article 1972 (Box-folder 2.19)
- Ezra Pound Criticism Checklist R. Corrigan 1972, oversize (Box-folder 2.20)
- The Willard Motley Papers at the University of Wisconsin J. Klinkowitz, J. Giles, J. O'Brien 1972 (Box-folder 2.21)
- Ellen Glasgow: An Essay in Bibliography Edgar E. MacDonald 1972 (Box-folder 2.22)
- A Washington Irving Manuscript William Scheick 1972 (Box-folder 2.23)
- News Notes and Briefer Notices 1972 (Box-folder 2.24)
- Index 1972 (Box-folder 2.25)
- Galley Proofs 1972, oversize (Box-folder 2.26)
- Galley Proofs and Page Proofs 1972, oversize (Box-folder 2.27)
- Proof Ellen Glasgow: An Essay in Bibliography Edgar MacDonald 1972 (Box-folder 2.28)
- Title pages, Volume III, number 1 1973 (Box-folder 3.1)
- Herman Melville's Mardi and A Voyage Thither: An Annotated Checklist D. Bowman 1973 (Box-folder 3.2)
- American Literary Manuscripts in the University of Iowa Library Frank Paluka 1973 (Box-folder 3.3)
- William Gilmore Simms C.S. Watson 1973 (Box-folder 3.4)
- Notes on the Text of F. Scott Fitzgerald's Early Success J. West 1973 (Box-folder 3.5)
- Book Reviews 1973 (Box-folder 3.6)
- News Notes and Briefer Notes 1973 (Box-folder 3.7)
- Galley Proofs 1973, Oversize (Box-folder 3.8-3.9)
- Galley and Page Proofs 1973, oversize (Box-folder 3.10)
- Correspondence, n.d. 1973 (Box-folder 3.11)
- Title Page and Notes, Volume III, number 2 1973 (Box-folder 3.12)
- Practical Editions: A Bad Resource for American Literary Study J. Katz 1973 (Box-folder 3.13)
- Biographical Notes on Ellen Glasgow Edgar E. MacDonald 1973 (Box-folder 3.14)
- The Contemporary Reception of the Boston Dial J. Myerson 1973 (Box-folder 3.15)
- The Testament of an American Schopehauer J. Slade 1973 (Box-folder 3.16)
- Edith Wharton: An Essay in Bibliography J. Tuttleton 1973 (Box-folder 4.1)
- Book Reviews 1973 (Box-folder 4.2)
- News Notes and Briefer Notices 1973 (Box-folder 4.3)
- Page Proofs 1973, oversize (Box-folder 4.4)
- Galley Proofs 1973, oversize (Box-folder 4.5-4.6)
- Correspondence, n.d. 1973 (Box-folder 4.7)
- Title page and notes, volume iv, number 1 1974 (Box-folder 4.8)
- The Bibliographical Study of Emily Dickinson W. Buckingham 1974 (Box-folder 4.9)
- Four New Works by Thomas HookerS. Bush Jr. 1974 (Box-folder 4.10)
- The Augustus Thomas Collection at UNC Jim G. Lewis 1974 (Box-folder 4.11)
- Dead Letters and Melville's Barleby H. Parker 1974 (Box-folder 4.12)
- Jean Tommer: An Annotated Checklist of Criticism J. Reilly 1974 (Box-folder 4.13)
- Book Reviews 1974 (Box-folder 4.14)
- News Notes and Briefer Notices 1974 (Box-folder 4.15)
- Galley Proofs 1974, oversize (Box-folder 4.16)
- Galley and page proofs 1974, oversize (Box-folder 4.17)
- Correspondence 1972, 1974 (Box-folder 4.18)
- Title page and Notes, volume IV, number 2 1974 (Box-folder 5.1)
- Reflections upon the CEAA by a Departing Editor P. Baender 1974 (Box-folder 5.2)
- First Twenty Years of E.A. Robinson Criticism R. Cary 1974 (Box-folder 5.3)
- The Letters of Sara Teasdale to Jessie Rittenhouse E. Cohen (Box-folder 5.4)
- Solomon Staddard's Sermon on the Lord's Supper T. Davis 1974 (Box-folder 5.5)
- Joseph Green's Satirical Poem on the Great Awakening J. Lemay 1974 (Box-folder 5.6)
- A Guide to the Letters of Willa Cather M. O'Connor 1974 (Box-folder 5.7)
- Book Reviews 1974 (Box-folder 5.8)
- News Notes and Briefer Notices 1974 (Box-folder 5.9)
- Correspondence 1973-1974 (Box-folder 5.10)
- Index 1974 (Box-folder 5.11)
- Galley proofs 1974, oversize (Box-folder 5.12-5.13)
- Galley and Page Proofs 1974, oversize (Box-folder 5.14)
- Frances Snow Compton Exposed P. Eppard 1975 (Box-folder 5.15)
- LHUS for the Fourth Time C. Holman 1975 (Box-folder 5.16)
- Two Early poems by Edward Albee P. Kolin 1975 (Box-folder 5.17)
- Far and Away the Most Original Genius.. G. Monteiro 1975 (Box-folder 5.18)
- The Weatherford-Hammond Mountain Collection of Berea College A. H. Perrin (Box-folder 5.19)
- The Franklin J. Meine Collections J. Swanson 1975 (Box-folder 6.1)
- Stephen Crane's Battalion NotesS. Wetheim 1975 (Box-folder 6.2)
- Walden: A Checklist of Literary Criticism.. A. Woodlief 1975 (Box-folder 6.3)
- Book Reviews 1975 (Box-folder 6.4)
- News Notes and Briefer Notices 1975 (Box-folder 6.5)
- Notes and Correspondence 1973-1975 (Box-folder 6.6)
- Galley Proofs 1975, oversize (Box-folder 6.7)
- Galley Proofs Interviews with Contemporary Writers J. McElrath 1975 (Box-folder 6.8)
- Galley and Page Proofs 1975, oversize (Box-folder 6.9)
- American Literary manuscripts in the Colby College Library R. Cary 1975 (Box-folder 6.10)
- The Dispersal of Samuel L. Clemens' Library Books A. Gribben 1975 (Box-folder 6.11)
- The Two Versions of Edward Taylor's Foundation Day Sermon D. Hall, T. Davis 1975 (Box-folder 6.12)
- Jones Very: An Essay in Bibliography D. Robinson 1975 (Box-folder 6.13)
- The Portrait of a Lady and the Anglo-American Press: An Annotated Checklist L. Taylor 1975 (Box-folder 6.14)
- Book Reviews 1975 (Box-folder 6.15)
- Galley Proofs of Book Reviews 1975 (Box-folder 6.16)
- Correspondence 1975 (Box-folder 6.17)
- Correspondence and Notes 1974-1975 (Box-folder 6.18)
- Introductory material 1975 (Box-folder 6.19)
- The Critical Reception of Robert Frost Peter Van Egmond 1975 (Box-folder 6.20)
- Another copy of L. Taylor article (Box-folder 6.21)
- Another copy of R. Cary article (Box-folder 6.22)
- Another copy of D. Hall and T. Davis article (Box-folder 6.23)
- Book Review corrections 1975 (Box-folder 6.24)
- Another copy of A. Gribben article (Box-folder 6.25)
- Thurber, A Biography Burton Bernstein 1975 (Box-folder 6.26)
- Book Reviews 1975 (Box-folder 6.27)
- Another copy of D. Robinson article (Box-folder 6.28)
- Galley Proofs 1975, oversize (Box-folder 6.29-6.33)
- Page Proofs 1976 (Box-folder 6.34)
- Robert Penn Warren's All the King's Men: An Annotated Checklist of Criticism James A. Grimshaw, Jr. 1975 (Box-folder 7.1)
- Charles Waddell Chestnutt: An Essay in Bibliography William L. Andrews 1975 (Box-folder 7.2)
- Alcott's Criticism of A Week Walter Hesford 1975 (Box-folder 7.3)
- American Literary Manuscripts: An Essay Review John C. Broderick 1975 (Box-folder 7.4)
- The Weatherford-Hammond Mountain Collection of Berea College Alfred H. Perrin 1975 (Box-folder 7.5)
- Handbooks for Italian Emigrants to the U.S.: A Bibliographical Survey Luigi Monga and Joseph V. Nardiello 1975 (Box-folder 7.6)
- Walter Hine Page on Southern Literature L. Moody Simms, Jr. 1975 (Box-folder 7.7)
- Author's Proof 1976 (Box-folder 7.8)
- Notes and Correspondence 1976 (Box-folder 7.9)
- Galley Proofs 1976, oversize (Box-folder 7.10)
- Galley Proofs 1976, oversize (Box-folder 7.11-7.13)
- Proof of All the King's Men 1975, oversize (Box-folder 7.14)
- Page Proofs 1976, oversize (Box-folder 7.16-7.17)